Sir, I want to tell something.
Yes, please tell me.
What happened?
Sir, when I speak English, people laugh at
me.
They smile and talk to each other.
I feel very bad.
I feel I am not good.
My English is very weak.
Oh, I understand.
You feel sad because people laugh when you
speak English.
But don't worry.
It's okay to make mistakes.
Everyone makes mistakes when they learn a
new language.
You are learning and learning takes time.
But sir, they speak fast.
I don't understand them.
When I try to talk, my words are wrong.
My friends laugh and I feel nervous.
It's fine.
You are not alone.
Many students feel like you.
You only need more practice and
confidence.
Let's practice together.
Let's speak simple English, okay?
Okay, sir.
We will use simple present tense today.
We use simple present tense to talk about
daily life, habits and routines.
For example, I say, I wake up at six o
'clock.
That means I do it every day.
You can say, I wake up at seven o'clock.
Let's try.
I wake up at seven o'clock.
Very good.
Say it again slowly.
I wake up at seven o'clock.
Perfect.
See, you speak well.
Now let's add more sentences.
After you wake up, what do you do?
I brush my teeth.
Good.
Say, I brush my teeth.
I brush my teeth.
Nice.
Now say two sentences together.
I wake up at seven o'clock.
I brush my teeth.
Excellent.
You are learning fast.
Let's continue.
After you brush your teeth, what do you
do?
I wash my face.
I take a shower.
Very good.
You can also say, I wash my face and take
a shower.
Try it.
I wash my face and take a shower.
Great job.
Remember, always speak slowly and clearly.
Don't be afraid.
Let's learn more.
After the shower, what do you do?
I eat breakfast.
Yes.
What do you eat for breakfast?
I eat eggs and bread.
Sometimes I drink milk.
Perfect.
You are using the simple present tense
correctly.
I eat eggs and bread.
I drink milk.
That's very good.
Thank you, sir.
Now, what do you do after breakfast?
I go to school.
Nice.
You can say, I go to school at eight o
'clock.
I go to school at eight o'clock.
Well done.
And what do you do at school?
I study English.
I write.
I read.
I talk to my friends.
Excellent.
You are speaking very well.
Let's make a small paragraph.
Listen to me first.
Then repeat after me.
I wake up at seven o'clock.
I brush my teeth.
I wash my face and take a shower.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school at eight o'clock.
I study English.
I talk to my friends.
I wake up at seven o'clock.
I brush my teeth.
I wash my face and take a shower.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school at eight o'clock.
I study English.
I talk to my friends.
Very good.
You spoke all sentences clearly.
See?
You can speak English.
You only need to practice more.
But sir, sometimes I forget words.
It's okay.
You can use simple words.
If you forget a word, don't stop.
Use another easy word.
Speak slowly.
The goal is to communicate not to be
perfect.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
Let's practice more daily activities.
What do you do in the afternoon?
I come home.
I eat lunch.
Very good.
You can say, I come home at one o'clock.
I eat lunch with my family.
I come home at one o'clock.
Excellent.
After lunch, what do you do?
I rest.
I watch TV.
Perfect.
You can also say, I take a rest.
I watch TV.
Try again.
I take a rest.
I watch TV.
Very nice.
Let's talk about the evening.
What do you do then?
I do my homework.
I help my mother.
Great sentences.
I do my homework.
I help my mother.
You are using the simple present tense
correctly every time.
Thank you, sir.
I feel happy now.
That's good.
You are improving.
Remember, practice every day.
Speak English at home, even alone.
Look in the mirror and talk.
You can say, I wake up.
I eat.
I go to work.
Practice makes you confident.
Sir, sometimes I want to talk,
but my mind stops.
I forget what to say.
That happens to everyone.
You can write your sentences first.
Read them aloud.
When you read, listen to your voice.
Try to repeat the same sentences every
day.
Slowly, you will remember without reading.
I will try.
Good.
Also, watch simple English videos.
Listen and repeat.
Don't be afraid of people laugh.
They may laugh, but you are learning
something good.
One day, they will stop laughing and start
listening to you.
Thank you, sir.
Your words make me feel strong.
That's my job.
I am proud of you.
You are brave to speak.
Now, let's say all your daily routine
again.
From morning to night.
Okay, sir.
I wake up at 7 o'clock.
I brush my teeth.
I wash my face and take a shower.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school at 8 o'clock.
I study English.
I talk to my friends.
I come home at 1 o'clock.
I eat lunch with my family.
I take a rest.
I watch TV.
I do my homework.
I help my mother.
Excellent.
And what do you do at night?
I eat dinner.
I read a book.
I sleep at 10 o'clock.
Wonderful.
That is your full daily routine.
You have spoken almost perfectly.
Now, if you keep practicing this every
day, your English will become strong.
I will practice, sir.
I will not be afraid anymore.
That's the spirit.
Just remember, English is not about being
perfect.
It is about communication.
Speak slowly.
Use simple words.
And repeat every day.
Thank you for teaching me in an easy way,
sir.
You're welcome.
I am happy to see your confidence.
Keep smiling.
Keep speaking.
And keep learning.
I will, sir.
I like English now.
It feels easy when you explain like this.
That's wonderful.
Remember, you can do it.
Speak English with joy and without fear.
You are improving every minute you
practice.
Yes, sir.
I will speak English every day.
Good.
Now, let's practice one more time
together.
Say after me, I speak English every day.
I practice every day.
I learn every day.
I speak English every day.
I practice every day.
I learn every day.
Excellent.
That's how you grow.
Keep repeating that sentence every morning
when you wake up.
I will do that.
I speak English every day.
Perfect.
You are doing great.
Sir, today I feel a little better.
Yesterday, I practice speaking in front of
the mirror.
But still, when I speak English with my
friends, I make many mistakes.
They don't laugh now, but I feel shy.
That is good progress.
You practiced, and that is the best way to
learn.
Making mistakes is a part of learning.
You should be proud that you were trying.
Tell me, what did you practice yesterday?
I said my daily routine again and again.
I said, I wake up at seven.
I brush my teeth.
I go to school.
But sometimes, I forget the verbs.
That's okay.
You are learning verbs slowly.
Today, we will talk more about the simple
present tense and verbs.
The simple present tense means we talk
about what we do every day.
It is like a habit.
You say, I go, I eat, I work.
We use the base form of the verb.
Do you understand?
Yes, sir.
We use the first form, right?
Very good.
We use the first form of the verb with I,
you, we, and they.
But when we use he, she, or it,
we add S or Es.
For example, I say, I go to school.
But we say, she goes to school.
Oh, yes.
I know that.
But I forget to add S.
Many learners forget that.
But don't worry.
You can fix it by practicing small
sentences every day.
Let's try.
Say after me, I eat breakfast.
I eat breakfast.
Good.
Now, change I to she.
She eats breakfast.
Listen carefully.
You should say, she eats breakfast.
She eats breakfast.
Perfect.
One more.
I play football.
Now, change it to he.
He plays football.
Excellent.
You are getting it right.
Let's do some more practice.
They study English.
Now, change it to she.
She studies English.
That's correct.
You see, when the verb ends with Y,
we change Y to I-E-S.
Like study becomes studies.
Yes, sir.
It is easy when you explain it.
Good.
Let's continue with some daily routine
practice using both I and she.
I will say one sentence, and you repeat
both versions.
I get up at 7 o'clock.
She gets up at 7 o'clock.
Nice.
I brush my teeth.
She brushes her teeth.
Excellent.
I go to school.
She goes to school.
Wonderful.
You are speaking very clearly.
Thank you, sir.
I think this practice helps me remember
the rules.
Yes.
That is how your brain learns through
repeating and listening.
Now, let's talk a little about other daily
actions.
What do you do in the morning before
school?
I help my mother.
Sometimes I make tea.
Very good.
What about your father?
What does he do in the morning?
He reads the newspaper.
He drinks tea.
Excellent.
You are using does correctly.
Now, remember, with he and she,
we also use does for questions.
For example, does he read the newspaper?
And the answer is yes, he does.
Try saying it.
Does he read the newspaper?
Yes, he does.
Great job.
Now, let's make some more examples.
Does she go to school?
Yes, she does.
Does he play football?
No, he doesn't.
Very nice.
When we say no, we use doesn't.
That means does not.
Yes, sir.
I understand now.
Perfect.
Let's make a small story about a day using
the simple present tense.
Listen first.
I get up at seven.
I brush my teeth.
I take a shower.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school.
I study English.
I play with my friends.
I come home at one o'clock.
I eat lunch.
I rest.
I do my homework.
I watch TV.
I go to bed at ten o'clock.
Now you try.
I get up at seven.
I brush my teeth.
I take a shower.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school.
I study English.
I play with my friends.
I come home at one o'clock.
I eat lunch.
I rest.
I do my homework.
I watch TV.
I go to bed at ten o'clock.
Wonderful.
That was clear and correct.
You are improving fast.
I am happy.
Before I could not say so many sentences.
Now it is easy.
That is because you are practicing every
day.
The more you speak, the better you become.
Now, let's use some question and answer
practice with your routine.
What time do you get up?
I get up at seven o'clock.
What do you eat for breakfast?
I eat bread and eggs.
When do you go to school?
I go to school at eight o'clock.
When do you come home?
I come home at one o'clock.
What do you do in the evening?
I do my homework.
I help my mother.
I watch TV.
Very good.
This is how you build small English
conversations.
These questions and answers help you talk
to anyone.
Yes, sir.
I can use them to talk with my friends
too.
Exactly.
You can ask your friends.
What time do you get up?
What do you eat for breakfast?
And they can answer.
This is good practice.
I will try that.
Good.
Now let's add a few new daily actions.
Say after me.
I walk to school.
I talk to my teacher.
I read a book.
I write in my notebook.
I listen to music.
I play with my little brother.
Very good.
All these are simple present tense
sentences.
They are about things we do every day.
Yes, sir.
I understand the simple present tense now.
That's great.
Remember one thing.
Practice makes you confident.
Speak these sentences every day when you
wake up.
Say I wake up.
I brush my teeth.
I take a shower.
You can even say them while doing the
action.
I can say I eat breakfast when I eat.
Exactly.
That helps your brain connect the word
with the action.
This is a powerful way to learn English.
I like that idea.
I will speak English while doing my work.
That's excellent.
You can also listen to English songs or
short stories and repeat the sentences.
This will help you improve pronunciation
too.
Sir, sometimes I feel I speak slowly.
Is that okay?
Yes, it is okay.
Speaking slowly is good for learning.
You will become faster with time.
Focus on being clear, not fast.
Yes, sir.
I will do that.
Good.
Keep using simple sentences.
You can say I walk.
I read.
I write.
I play.
I help.
These are strong and easy.
You don't need long or difficult words
now.
Yes, sir.
Short sentences help me feel more
confident.
That is true.
Confidence is more important than speed.
You are learning step by step and you are
doing great.
Thank you, sir.
I will keep practicing the simple present
tense.
That's very good.
When you use English every day,
it becomes natural.
You don't need to think about grammar.
You will just speak it.
I will try my best.
I know you will.
You are improving every day because you
practice.
And that is the secret of learning
English.
Sir, today I want to learn how to speak
English with other people.
When I meet someone new, I feel shy.
I don't know what to say first.
That's a good question.
Many students feel the same.
When we talk to others, we can use simple
present tense to say what we do,
what we like, and who we are.
Let's practice small conversations.
Okay, sir.
I want to learn that.
Good.
First, when you meet someone, you can say,
hello.
How are you?
The other person can answer, I'm fine.
Thank you.
Let's try.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Thank you.
And you?
I'm fine too.
Perfect.
That's how we start a simple talk.
After that, you can ask, what do you do?
Or where do you live?
Try asking me.
What do you do?
I am a teacher.
I teach English.
What do you do?
I am a student.
I study English.
Excellent.
See, you used simple present tense
correctly.
I study English.
It tells what you do every day.
Now, let's add more questions.
You can ask, where do you live?
Where do you live?
I live in Lahore.
I live in Karachi.
Very nice.
You can also ask about hobbies.
You can say, what do you like to do?
Or, what do you do in your free time?
What do you like to do?
I like to read books.
What about you?
I like to listen to music.
Great.
All these sentences are in the simple
present tense.
They talk about what you do every day or
what you like.
Yes, sir.
I understand now.
It's easy when you show examples.
That's right.
Let's make a longer conversation using
these ideas.
I will start.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Thank you.
How are you?
I'm fine too.
What do you do?
I am a student.
I study English.
That's nice.
Where do you study?
I study at city school.
Very good.
What time do you go to school?
I go to school at eight o'clock.
And when do you come home?
I come home at one o'clock.
Good.
What do you do after school?
I eat lunch.
I take a rest.
Then I do my homework.
Excellent.
What do you like to do in the evening?
I like to watch TV and listen to music.
That's great.
This is a full conversation about your
day.
You used the simple present tense in every
sentence.
Thank you, sir.
I think I can speak like this when I need
someone new.
Yes, you can.
You just need to remember small sentence
patterns.
For example, I like.
I go.
I do.
I have.
Let's practice with those.
Okay, sir.
Say after me.
I like tea.
I go to school.
I do my homework.
I have many friends.
Good.
You can use these short patterns to make
many sentences.
For example, I like apples.
I go to the park.
I do my work.
I have a brother.
Yes, sir.
I can make many now.
I like chocolate.
I go to the market.
I do my homework.
I have a sister.
Excellent.
You are using them correctly.
That's how you build confidence.
Now, let's make some questions using do
and does.
Remember, we use do for I, you,
we, they and does for he, she,
it.
For example, do you like coffee or does he
play football?
Okay, sir.
Let me try.
Do you like music?
Yes, I do.
Does she go to school?
Yes, she does.
Do they play football?
No, they don't.
Do you read books?
Yes, I do.
Very good.
Now you are making questions.
That's how we have real conversations.
You can use these every day with friends.
Sir, sometimes I feel scared to ask
questions.
That's normal.
But the more you ask, the easier it
becomes.
People will answer and you will learn from
them.
If you make a mistake, just smile and
continue.
Yes, sir.
I will try to talk more.
Great.
Let's practice talking about your family
now.
Tell me about your family in simple
sentences.
I have four people in my family.
My father works in an office.
My mother cooks food.
My brother studies in school.
I study English.
Excellent.
Now, let's add some more details.
What time does your father go to work?
He goes to work at nine o'clock.
What time does he come home?
He comes home at six o'clock.
Good.
What does your mother do in the afternoon?
She cooks lunch and cleans the house.
Very good.
You are using does and s endings
correctly.
That's a big improvement.
Thank you, sir.
I remember your examples.
That's the key to learning.
Listen and repeat.
Repeat every day.
When you repeat, your tongue becomes
comfortable with English sounds.
Let's repeat a few more.
He works in an office.
She cooks dinner.
He reads books.
She watches TV.
Very good.
These are simple but useful sentences.
You can talk about anyone using these.
Yes, sir.
I can talk about my family, my friends,
or my teacher.
Exactly.
Now, let's talk about likes and dislikes.
This is also in simple, present tense.
You can say, I like apples.
I don't like bananas.
She likes tea.
He doesn't like milk.
Try some.
I like chocolate.
I don't like coffee.
She likes music.
He doesn't like noise.
Very nice.
You said everything correctly.
Remember, when we use doesn't,
we don't add s to the verb.
For example, he doesn't like.
Not he doesn't likes.
Yes, sir.
I understand.
Good.
Let's add a few small dialogues now.
I'll say something and you answer.
Do you like English?
Yes, I do.
What do you do every morning?
I wake up early.
I brush my teeth.
I eat breakfast.
Where do you go after breakfast?
I go to school.
What do you do in the evening?
I study English and listen to songs.
Excellent.
You are talking naturally now.
This is how conversations happen.
Simple, short, clear.
I feel happy when I can answer without
stopping.
That's great.
You should feel proud.
Every small step makes you better.
Keep using the simple present tense.
It helps you talk about your life,
your habits, your family, and your likes.
Yes, sir.
I can feel I am learning.
You are.
Just remember to speak slowly,
think in English, and use small sentences.
Every day you can start your morning with
10 sentences like, I wake up.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school.
I study.
I come home.
I watch TV.
That will make your English natural.
I will do that.
I will speak every day and not be shy.
That's very good.
Keep going and you will become more
confident.
Sir, I want to tell you something.
Yesterday, when I spoke English with my
classmates, they laughed at me again.
I felt very bad.
I wanted to stop speaking.
I think my English is not good.
Oh, I understand how you feel.
It hurts when people laugh, doesn't it?
But listen, that doesn't mean your English
is bad.
It means you are trying and they are not.
You are learning and that is something to
be proud of.
But sir, when I talk, I forget words.
My mind goes blank.
I start one sentence and then stop.
Everyone looks at me.
I feel so small.
That's okay.
Every learner feels that way.
Even native speakers forget words
sometimes.
You are learning a new language.
You must make mistakes.
Mistakes are not bad.
They are part of learning.
Without mistakes, we can't grow.
Sometimes I think maybe English is not for
me.
Maybe I can never speak well.
No, don't say that.
You already speak.
You were talking to me now and I
understand you.
That means you can speak.
You just need more practice and more
confidence.
When you speak, don't think about what
people say.
Just think about what you want to say.
But sir, when people laugh, it makes me
nervous.
My hands shake.
I forget everything.
That's normal too.
Many people feel nervous.
You can train your mind to stay calm.
Take a deep breath, smile and speak
slowly.
You don't have to speak fast.
Clear and slow English is better.
I try to speak fast like others.
Maybe that's my mistake.
Yes, you don't need to copy others.
Speak at your own speed.
Let's practice something now.
When you talk about your day, use short
sentences.
You can say, I wake up.
I brush my teeth.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school.
Say it with me.
I wake up.
I brush my teeth.
I eat breakfast.
I go to school.
Good.
Simple and clear.
That's beautiful English.
You see, you are already speaking
correctly in the simple present tense.
Yes, sir.
I can say these sentences easily.
That's because these are daily routine
actions.
The more you say them, the easier it
becomes.
Now let's add a few more.
I come home.
I eat lunch.
I do my homework.
I take a rest.
I watch TV.
I sleep.
I come home.
I eat lunch.
I do my homework.
I take a rest.
I watch TV.
I sleep.
Very good.
You see, you can describe your full day.
Now, if someone asks, what do you do every
day, you can answer easily.
Yes, sir.
I can say, I wake up early.
I brush my teeth.
I go to school.
I study.
I come home.
I eat lunch.
I watch TV.
I sleep.
Perfect.
You just spoke eight correct sentences in
English.
Thank you, sir.
When I speak slowly like this,
I feel better.
That's the right way.
Always speak slowly, clearly, and
confidently.
Remember, English is not a race.
It's a skill.
You build it step by step.
Sir, sometimes I also forget when to use S
with verbs.
Like he play or he plays.
I get confused.
That's a very common mistake.
Let's practice it.
In simple present tense, when we talk
about he, she, or it, we add S to the verb.
For example, he plays football.
She cooks food.
It rains in summer.
Okay.
He plays football.
She cooks food.
It rains in summer.
Good.
Now make a few sentences yourself.
He reads a book.
She sings a song.
It shines in the sky.
Excellent.
You used S correctly.
Now remember, when we use I, you,
we, or they, we don't add S.
For example, I play football.
We study English.
They eat lunch.
I see.
So I play, but he plays.
Exactly.
That's the rule.
Let's repeat it a few times together.
I play.
He plays.
I read.
She reads.
I cook.
She cooks.
I go.
He goes.
Wonderful.
You are learning fast.
You see, English becomes easy when we
break it into small steps.
Yes, sir.
I feel more confident now.
That's great.
Now let's practice questions again using
do and does.
You can ask, do you like apples or does he
like apples?
Okay.
Do you like music?
Yes, I do.
Does she like music?
Yes, she does.
Very good.
Let's try negative sentences, too.
I don't like coffee.
He doesn't like milk.
Great.
Always remember, after doesn't,
we don't add S to the verb.
So he doesn't like, not he doesn't like.
Yes, sir.
I will remember that.
Good.
Now let's use this in a small
conversation.
I will ask.
You answer.
Do you get up early?
Yes, I do.
What time do you wake up?
I wake up at seven o'clock.
Do you eat breakfast?
Yes, I eat breakfast every day.
What do you eat?
I eat bread and eggs.
What do you do after breakfast?
I go to school.
Excellent.
You just had a small talk about your daily
life.
Sir, now I understand how to talk with
others.
I can ask and answer simple questions.
That's right.
You can talk about yourself, your family,
and your daily routine.
For example, my mother cooks breakfast.
My father goes to work.
My sister studies.
These are all simple, present-tent
sentences.
My mother cooks food.
My father drives a car.
My sister goes to school.
Perfect.
You are improving.
Now, if someone laughs, just smile.
You know that you are learning.
They may laugh today,
but one day they will listen
carefully because your English
will be clear and confident.
I hope so, sir.
I want to speak like you one day.
You will.
Just keep speaking every day.
Practice in front of a mirror.
Talk to yourself.
Say things like, I wake up.
I wash my face.
I go out.
I meet my friends.
Repeat and repeat.
I can do that.
I can practice in my room every morning.
That's a great idea.
You can also write short notes about your
day.
For example, write, I go to school.
I study English.
I talk with my teacher.
Writing helps you remember.
Yes, sir.
I like writing, too.
Wonderful.
Keep writing and reading aloud.
Listen to English songs or short stories.
Try to repeat them.
Your tongue will become used to English
sounds.
I will do that, sir.
Thank you for helping me feel better.
You are very welcome.
Remember, learning English is not about
being perfect.
It's about being brave enough to speak
even when others laugh.
Every time you speak, you improve.
Every time you try, you win a small
victory.
I understand now, sir.
I will not stop speaking.
I will keep trying every day.
That's the spirit.
You are doing great.
Sir, today I tried to speak English again
with my friends.
I spoke slowly, but they still laughed a
little.
This time, I didn't feel too bad.
I remembered what you said and I just
smiled.
But I want to speak better.
I want people to listen to me,
not laugh.
I am very proud of you.
You didn't stop speaking even when they
laughed.
That's real courage.
Every time you speak, you become better.
Tell me, what did you say to your friends
today?
I said, I wake up early and I go to
school.
Then I told them, I study English every
day.
But one word I said wrong and they
laughed.
That's okay.
Maybe they don't
understand what learning
feels like, but you are
learning the right way.
You used the simple present tense very
well.
I wake up early.
I go to school.
I study English.
Those are perfect sentences.
When I speak like that, I feel calm.
I don't need big words.
I just want to speak correctly and
clearly.
Exactly.
Simple English is powerful English.
Most people in the world speak using
short, clear sentences.
You can do the same.
Let's talk about more things you do every
day.
What time do you wake up?
I wake up at seven o'clock.
What do you do after you wake up?
I brush my teeth.
I wash my face.
I eat breakfast.
Excellent.
What do you eat for breakfast?
I eat bread and eggs.
Sometimes I drink milk.
That's great.
Now tell me what you do after breakfast.
I go to school.
I study.
I talk to my teacher.
I play with my friends.
Very good.
You are making perfect daily routine
sentences.
You can even make them longer now.
You can say, I go to school at eight o
'clock.
I study English in science.
I play with my friends during break time.
Try it.
I go to school at eight o'clock.
I study English in science.
I play with my friends during break time.
Wonderful.
You see how fluent you sound now?
Yes, sir.
When I speak slowly, I can say everything
clearly.
That's right.
You are speaking clearly and that is more
important than speaking fast.
You can practice by talking about your
afternoon too.
What do you do when you come home?
I eat lunch.
Then I take a rest.
I do my homework.
After that, I help my mother.
Excellent.
You are using verbs correctly in the
simple present tense.
Eat, take, do, help.
These are all action words.
They show what you do every day.
Yes, sir.
I understand now.
The simple present tense is about things I
do every day.
Exactly.
And also about things you like or don't
like.
Let's practice that.
What do you like to do after school?
I like to listen to music.
I like to draw pictures.
I like to talk with my friends.
Very good.
And what don't you like to do?
I don't like to wash dishes.
I don't like to wake up very early.
I don't like to fight with my brother.
Great.
That's how you express your feelings in
English.
I like.
I don't like.
It's easy and natural.
Now let's make some sentences about other
people using he and she.
Tell me about your father.
My father works in an office.
He drives a car.
He drinks tea in the morning.
Very good.
Tell me about your mother.
My mother cooks food.
She cleans the house.
She watches TV in the evening.
Excellent.
And your brother?
My brother goes to school.
He plays football.
He studies math.
Perfect.
You are using he and she sentences very
well.
Remember, with he, she and it,
we add S to the verb.
Works, drives, plays, studies.
Yes, sir.
I remember that rule now.
Good.
Now let's make it more fun.
I will see a sentence and you tell me if
it's correct or not.
He play football.
It's wrong.
It should be he plays football.
Excellent.
She go to school.
Wrong.
She goes to school.
They like tea.
Wrong.
Very good.
You are becoming confident.
Thank you, sir.
I feel better when I can find mistakes
myself.
That's the sign of progress.
Now let's practice some questions you can
use in daily life.
For example, what do you eat for lunch?
What time do you go to school?
Do you like reading books?
What do you eat for lunch?
I eat rice and vegetables.
What time do you go to school?
I go to school at eight o'clock.
Do you like reading books?
Yes, I do.
I like reading English stories.
I want to read English stories too,
but I find them difficult.
That's normal.
Start with short stories.
Read slowly.
When you find a new word, don't stop.
Try to understand from the sentence.
Then read aloud.
Reading aloud helps your speaking.
I can do that.
I will read one page every day.
That's a wonderful plan.
When you read, say the sentences in your
mind and then repeat them out loud.
For example, I wake up.
I eat breakfast.
When you speak again and again,
your mouth remembers the sound.
Yes, sir.
When I repeat, it feels easier.
Exactly.
Listening and repeating is the best
practice.
You can listen to small English videos or
short podcasts.
Listen carefully.
Pause and repeat what they say.
I listen to English songs sometimes,
but I don't understand all the words.
That's okay.
You can enjoy the rhythm and catch small
words.
Even when you don't understand everything,
your ears get used to English sounds.
Slowly, you will start to understand more.
That's true.
Sometimes, I understand a few words and
feel happy.
That's a great feeling.
Celebrate small progress.
Each new word you understand is a step
forward.
You are not competing with anyone.
You are learning for yourself.
Yes, sir.
I want to speak English so I can talk to
people everywhere.
That's a wonderful goal.
English helps you connect with the world.
But remember, it's not about being
perfect.
It's about being brave.
When you speak, speak with confidence.
Even if you make a small mistake,
keep talking.
I will try, sir.
I want to be brave when I speak.
You already are brave.
You speak even when others laugh.
That shows strength.
Every time you use English, your brain
becomes stronger.
Every sentence you say brings you closer
to fluency.
I understand now.
I just need to keep going, not stop.
Yes, make English part of your daily life.
When you wake up, say good morning.
When you eat, say I eat breakfast.
When you sleep, say good night.
Talk in English to yourself every day.
I can do that easily.
I can speak small sentences while doing
things.
That's perfect.
That's how children
learn their first language
by speaking small
sentences again and again.
You can do the same.
Thank you, sir.
You make English feel simple.
Because it is simple when you use it
daily.
Don't wait for big lessons or big words.
Just speak what you know.
Smile, be confident and enjoy the process.
Yes, sir.
I feel more confident now.
I will speak English every day no matter
what people say.
That's the best promise you can make to
yourself.